Gould, Samuel; Papers apap058
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Speeches, 1954-1985; Undated; 2; 2.50 cubic ft.
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Higher Education for the Twenty First Century," 40th Anniversary Celebration, University of Bridgeport, 1967 May 01 (Box 2 (2-Speeches), Folder 145)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Inauguration of President Hill, Downstate Medical Center, 1967 May 05 (Box 2 (2-Speeches), Folder 146)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Introduction of Governor Rockefeller, Hospital Dedication, Downstate Medical Center, 1967 May 05 (Box 2 (2-Speeches), Folder 147)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Continuing Education in State University: Obligations and Responsibilities," State University Conference on Continuing Education, 1967 May 08 (Box 2 (2-Speeches), Folder 148)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Focus on the Student," Faculty Day, Kingsborough Community College, 1967 May 12 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 1)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Inauguration of President Meyerson, State University at Buffalo, 1967 May 29 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 2)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Turning the Hourglass," Commencement, Vassar College, 1967 June 04 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 3)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Role of the Two Year College in Public Higher Education," Conference of Two Year College Faculty, 1967 June 14 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 4)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Two Worlds Out of Many," Commencement, Monroe Community College, 1967 June 18 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 5)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "State University of New York," NYS Society of Newspaper Editors, 1967 June 19 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 6)
  - Educational Broadcasting Corporation, Remarks, 1967 July 02 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 7)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Arts in Higher Education: Valid or Valueless?" Tanglewood Symposium, 1967 September 28 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 8)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Arts in Higher Education: Valid or Valueless?" Luncheon Meeting, Twentieth Century Fund, 1967 September 29 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 9)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Leadership and Stewardship: The Role of the Community College Trustee," Annual Conference, Association of Boards and Councils, 1967 September 29 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 10)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Introduction of Governor Rockefeller, Dedication Ceremonies, 1967 October 05 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 11)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "A Look at Educational Philosophy," International Philosophy Year, 1967 October 07 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 12)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Whose Goals for Higher Education?" Annual Conference, American Council on Education, 1967 October 12 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 13)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Great is the Art of Beginning," Brandeis University Dinner, 1967 October 15 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 14)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Remarks--Inauguration of President Brown, State University Agricultural and Technology College, 1967 October 21 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 15)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "An Age of Academic Cooperation," Association of State Colleges and Universities, 1967 November 13 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 16)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Index of Speeches, 1968 January-1970 October (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 17)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Dilemmas of Discontent," Cortland Chamber of Commerce, Banquet, 1968 January 31 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 18)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks and Panel Discussion--Commission on Independent Colleges, 1968 February 06 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 19)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Freedom and Responsibility of the University," Statement to Joint Legislative Committee on Higher Education of the State of New York, 1968 February 29 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 20)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Comments on the Bundy Report, 1968 March 12 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 21)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The University and the Challenge of Change," Centennial Lecture Series, University of California, 1968 March 07 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 22)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The University, the Student, and the Community," Conference, New York State County Officers Association, 1968 April 02 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 23)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "An Appreciation of Excellence," Westchester County Scholastic Achievement Dinner, 1968 April 03 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 24)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Impact of Technology Upon Educational Innovation," Action Forum, U.S. Chamber of Commerce, 1968 April 29 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 25)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Expanding Opportunities," SUNY Presidents' Conference on the Disadvantaged, 1968 April 30 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 26)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Inauguration of President Fretwell, State University College at Buffalo, 1968 May 10 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 27)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "An Appreciation of Excellence," Senator Earl W. Brydges Scholarship Dinner, 1968 June 03 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 28)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "A Place to Stand," Commencement, State University College at New Paltz, 1968 June 09 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 29)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The University Library in an Urban Setting," Dedication of Hillman Library, State University at Plattsburgh, 1968 September 06 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 30)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Possibilities for Higher Education in the Mid-Hudson Region," Dinner Meeting, Pattern for Progress, 1968 September 11 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 31)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks--Inauguration of President Satre, Community College of the Finger Lakes, 1968 September 19 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 32)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "On the Progress of the University," Conference of State University Presidents, 1968 September 20 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 33)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The University and a World of Dilemmas," Annual Dinner, New Publishers Association, 1968 September 23 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 34)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Present World of the University," Annual Dinner, Association of College Admission Counselors, 1968 September 26 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 35)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Vision and Realization," Dedication and Inauguration Exercises, North Country Community College, 1968 September 27 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 36)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Mankind is Our Business," St. Pius X Holy Name Communion Breakfast, 1968 September 29 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 37)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Corporation and the Arts: A Partnership for Creativity," Conference on the Arts, 1968 October 03 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 38)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-SUNY Conference on Continuing Education in Health Sciences, 1968 October 04 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 39)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Student and His College," Opening Convocation, Pace College, 1968 October 08 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 40)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks--Biomedical Communications Network Dedication, Upstate Medical Center, 1968 October 18 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 41)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Higher Education: The Eye of the Hurricane," Inauguration Dinner, Minnesota State College System, 1968 October 28 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 42)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Groundbreaking, State University at Buffalo, 1968 October 31 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 43)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "On Doing One's Own Thing," Annual Meeting, Association of Urban Universities, 1968 November 04 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 44)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Dedication Exercises, NYS College of Agriculture, 1968 December 05 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 45)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "A Bill of Divorcement," Midyear Commencement Exercises, University of Akron, 1968 December 15 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 46)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Role of the State University in New York State," Members Council, Commerce and Industry Association of New York, 1969 January 21 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 47)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Instructional Trends in Higher Education," Conference, Science Research Associates, 1969 January 31 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 48)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Educational Development and International Education," Sixth Conference on International Education, 1969 February 20 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 49)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The University, Arts and Society," SUNY Convocation on the Arts, 1969 April 18 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 50)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "So Great a Cloud of Witness," Testimonial Dinner, 1969 June 02 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 51)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Fall Meeting of Presidents, 1969 September 19 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 52)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Academic Condition," Abstracts of Lectures 1, 2, and 3, Colgate Sesquicentennial, 1969 September 22-1969 September 24 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 53)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Academic Condition: Lecture 1, The University Today, Confronted but not Confounded", 1969 September 22 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 54)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Academic Condition: Lecture 2, The University Today: Architect of American Society", 1969 September 23 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 55)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Academic Condition: Lecture 3, The University Tomorrow, Reformist or Revolutionary", 1969 September 24 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 56)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Inauguration of President Bluemle, Upstate Medical Center, 1969 September 26 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 57)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Dedication, Campus Activities Building, Upstate Medical Center, 1969 September 26 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 58)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Remarks-Inauguration of President Jones, State University College at Cortland, 1969 October 11 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 59)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Introduction of Governor Rockefeller, Dedication Convocation, State University College at Fredonia, 1969 October 17 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 60)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Private and Public Higher Education: Diversity Without Division," Annual Meeting, Pennsylvania Association of Colleges and Universities, 1969 October 20 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 61)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Management in a Knowledge Society," 3rd International Conference of Management Consultants, 1969 October 30 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 62)
  - Summary of Publicly Expressed Ideas, Bibliographies of Speeches, 1969; Undated (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 63)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Governance in Higher Education During the Seventies," Sixth Annual Conference, The Leadership Roles of the Trustees, 1970 February 10 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 64)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Statement-Dedication, Edward H. Butler Library, State University College at Buffalo, 1970 April 14 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 65)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "Retreat From Reason," Commencement, University of Pittsburgh, 1970 April 26 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 66)
  - SUNY Chancellor, Closing Remarks--Annual Conference, Associated Councils of the Arts, 1970 May 23 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 67)
  - SUNY Chancellor, "The Growing Assault on Reason," Commencement, Albany Medical College, 1970 May 28 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 68)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Damn the Torpedoes-Full Speed Ahead!" Remarks Delivered at the 53rd Annual Meeting of the American Council on Education, 1970 October 08 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 69)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, Index of Speeches and Articles, Chairman, Commission on Non-Traditional Study, 1971-1974 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 70)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Public Affairs and Continuing Education," Center For Continuing Education, University of Notre Dame, 1971 January 08 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 71)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "New York: The State University," Voice of America, Forum Broadcast Lecture, 1971 February 28 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 72)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Bridging the Interpretation Gap," American Association for Higher Education Conference, 1971 March 15 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 73)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "A New Chaos or a New Culture," National Association of Student Personnel Administrators, 1971 March 30 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 74)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "The College Presidency in a New Era," Institute for College and University Administrators, 1971 June 25 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 75)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Today's Education with Yesterday's Goals," Banquet, Education Commission of the States, 1971 July 07 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 76)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Community Colleges and Non-Traditional Study," Sixth Annual Community College Conference, 1971 July 28 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 77)
  - Chairman of Commission on Non-Traditional Study, "Prospects for the Non-Traditional Study," Annual Conference, Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges, 1971 October 11 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 78)
  - Chairman of Commission on Non-Traditional Study, "A Circle That Includes," Annual Meeting, College Entrance Examination Board, 1971 October 25 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 79)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "The Birth of a Non-Traditional Tradition," Annual Institutional Conference, Educational Testing Service, 1971 October 31 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 80)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Financial Implications of Non-Traditional Study," Annual Conference, National Association of College and University Business Officers, 1971 November 23 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 81)
  - Chairman of Commission on Non-Traditional Study, "The Anatomy of Non-Traditional Education," Annual Conference, Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1971 November 29 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 82)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Re-Focusing on the Future," Annual Conference, Academic Deans of the Southern States, 1971 November 30 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 83)
  - Chairman of Commission on Non-Traditional Study, "Developments in Non-Traditional Study," Governor's Conference on Post High-School Education, 1971 December 07 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 84)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "A Non-Traditional Tradition," Inauguration Address, Mercy College, 1972 February 25 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 85)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Less Talk, More Actions (The Dangers and Possibilities of the External Degree)," Annual Conference, American Association for Higher Education, 1972 March 06 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 86)
  - Chairman of Commission on Non-Traditional Study, "Developments in Non-Traditional Study," Cooperative Academic Planning Workshop, Institute for Services to Education, 1972 April 20 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 87)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "New Approaches to Education in the 70's," National Association of College Admissions Counselors, 1972 May 09 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 88)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "New Arrangements for Learning," Southern Regional Education Board, 1972 July 21 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 89)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Open Learning: An Old Concept With New Perspectives," as President, Institute for Educational Development, ca. February 1973 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 90)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Alternative Approaches to Higher Education," Phi Beta Kappa Association of Fredrick County, 1973 April 25 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 91)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "The National Scene," New Jersey College Fund Association, 1973 May 15 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 92)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Changes and Challenges in the Academic Career-The Teacher: Still a Partner in Learning," Danforth Associate National Conference, 1973 August 27 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 93)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "A Program in Education for a Changing Society," APEX background paper, 1973 September (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 94)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Variety and Abundance: Are These Appropriate Educational Goals?" Educational Symposium, 1973 November 02 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 95)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, Conference on "Liberal Arts College and the Experienced Learner", 1973 December 12 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 96)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Open Learning: An Old Concept With New Perspectives," The National Conference on Open Learning in Higher Education, 1974 January 16 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 97)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, Abstract of "Open Learning: An Old Concept With New Perspectives," The National Conference on Open Learning in Higher Education, 1974 January 16 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 98)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Changing Patterns in Higher Education," Annual Meeting, American Assembly of Collegiate Schools of Business, 1974 April 23 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 99)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Projecting a New Image of the Elderly," Southern Regional Conference, The National Council on the Aging, 1974 April 30 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 100)
  - President of Institute for Educational Development, "The University in a Changing World," Seminar Cosponsored by United States Information Service, Venezuelan Ministry of Education, 1974 May 15 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 101)
  - President of Institute for Educational Development, "Alternate Approaches to Higher Education," Green Bay University Lecture Series, 1974 September 24 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 102)
  - President of Institute for Educational Development, "Teaching Improvement Through Organizational Change," International Conference on Improving University Teaching, 1974 October 07 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 103)
  - President of Institute for Educational Development, "The Library as a Source of Learning," Fall Conference, Illinois Library Association, 1974 October 25 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 104)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Charge to the Conference," Second Annual Conference on Open Learning, 1975 June 17 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 105)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Changes in Attitudes Toward Learning," Prepare for Program in Education for a Changing Society, Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1976 January (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 106)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Non-Traditional Education and the States: Strategies and Implications," Educational Commission of the States Conference, 1976 May 17 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 107)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Higher Education: For Whom and By Whom?" Staff Development Seminar, University of Maryland, 1976 June 01 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 108)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Great is the Art of Beginning," Fall Convocation, SUNY College at Purchase, 1976 September 15 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 109)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Voluntarism: An Expanding Circle of Concern," White House Conference on Voluntarism (NSVP), 1976 September 20 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 110)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Developing Partnerships: The Arts Higher Education and the Community," Twentieth Annual Conference, ACUCAA, 1976 December 12 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 111)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Today's Education with Yesterday's Goals-Some Reasons for Alternative Approaches to Learning," Convocation, Mary Baldwin College, 1977 February 07 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 112)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "The Public Library: Core of Conscience and Community," Annual Conference, Illinois Library Association, 1978 January 22 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 113)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Libraries to Match Our Times," Community College Learning Resources Conference, 1978 March 06 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 114)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Education to Match Our Times," Chautauqua Institution, 1978 August 14 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 115)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "The Community as a Resource for Learning," Oklahoma Library Association Conference, 1979 March 22 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 116)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Quality and Credibility," Eighth World Wide Armed Services Education Conference, 1979 April 09 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 117)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Developing a National Need Analysis," First World Conference on Continuing Engineering Education, 1979 April 25-1979 April 27 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 118)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "The Second Time Around," Commencement Address, Aquinas College, 1980 May 10 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 119)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Higher Education and the Information Society: Are We About to Miss the Brass Ring Again?" Human Values and Higher Education in the 21st Century, Breakfast Seminar Series, 1983 November 18 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 120)
  - SUNY Chancellor Emeritus, "Is it Really One Minute to Midnight?" Annual Convocation, SUNY at Albany, 1985 April 23 (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 121)
  - Bibliographies of Speeches, Undated (Box 3 (2-Speeches), Folder 122)
- Reports and Published and Unpublished Works, 1936-1980; Undated; 3; 0.81 cubic ft.
  Contains articles, reports and rough drafts by Gould while a student at the Naval War College (1945), a consultant to the Office of the Assistant Secretary of State for Educational and Cultural Affairs (1961), president of the Educational Broadcasting Corporation (1962), chancellor of SUNY (1964-70), and chairman of the Commission on Non-Traditional Study (1973), relating to his interest in educational reform. The series includes a summary of publicly expressed ideas with a bibliography and listing of speeches. Also included is a carbon copy of an unpublished monograph entitled "The Emerging Role of Management in Higher Education" (ca. 1952). The series also contains three books on the subject of educational reform. Two were written by Gould, Knowledge is Not Enough (1959) and Today's Academic Condition (1970), and one, Diversity By Design (1975), was written jointly by the Commission on Non-Traditional Study. Gould wrote the preface to this book. This series contains correspondence between Gould and his publishers on the publication of his books, requests from editors of journals and magazines for permission to publish his writings, and a few letters from friends of Gould and his wife requesting copies of publications.
  - "The Standard of Literary Criticism in the Westminster Review, paper by Samuel B. Gould, 1936 (Oversized 1)
  - Post-War Establishment of the United States, Naval War College Thesis written by Gould, 1945 (Oversized 3)
  - Letter for the News Press, University Edition, President, Antioch College, ca. 1959 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 123)
  - Welcome Message for Frosh Bible, ca. 1959 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 124)
  - Introduction to College Student Government, by Professor Gordon J. Klopf, ca. 1959 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 125)
  - An Organizational Survey of the Office of the Assistant Secretary of State for Educational and Cultural Affairs and the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs", 1961 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 126)
  - "A Broad Design For Educational Television," Educational Broadcasting Company President, 1962 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 127)
  - "Extracts From Dr. Gould's Address `Fanning the Embers'"Hunter Alumni Quarterly, 1963 April (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 128)
  - "The Teacher's Impact on the Curriculum," Correspondence and Writing for School and Society, 1964-1965 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 129)
  - State University Newsletters, 1964-1967; 1985 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 130)
  - Correspondence about Books, 1964-1970 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 131)
  - "The Shaping of a University," Report of the President, State University of New York, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 132)
  - "The Role of the Student in the Life of the University," NASPA Journal Article and Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 133)
  - Journal Articles Written by Gould and Correspondence, 1966-1967; 1971-1979 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 134-135)